# RESUME

#### SK INSAN AHAMED

S/O: SK Md Mahasin Ali Kurumba, Purbagopalpur, Purba Bardhhaman, West Bengal, India, 713143



+91 7679488992, +91 9064199055 <u>skinsanahamed@gmail.com</u>



#### **PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE**

Looking for an entry into a world-class, highly professional Organization with a challenging and competitive environment, where I can use my knowledge base as well as a personal attribute to achieve the organizational goal.

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Good experience of practical in a range of satellite remote sensing data utilization, processing, interpretation, and analysis with emphasis on Forestry, Geomorphology, Hydrogeology, Crop Analysis, and Natural hazard, etc. Good experience in Image processing & Geographical Information System software.

## **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION**

ACADEMIC EDUCATION	BOARD/UNIVERSITY	YEAR	DIVISION	Percentage of marks
				(%)
SECONDARY (10TH)	West Bengal Board	2008	1 <sup>ST</sup>	69.5
	SECONDARY EDUCATION,			
HIGHER SECONDARY (12TH)	WEST BENGAL COUNCIL OF	2010	$2^{\text{ND}}$	59.6
	HIGHER SECONDARY			
	EDUCATION			
GRADUATION (HONORS' IN	VINOBA BHAVE UNIVERSITY,	2013	$2^{\text{ND}}$	54.62
Geography)	Hazaribag, Jharkhand			
POST-GRADUATION IN	NORTH ORISSA UNIVERSITY	2015	1 <sup>ST</sup>	70.90
REMOTE SENSING AND GIS				
(M.Sc.)				

TECHNICAL SKILLS		
Digital Image Processing, GIS Software	Orth rectification, Erdas Imagine, Leica Photogrammetry Suite, Arc GIS, Arc Scene, Auto Cad Map. Google Earth, Adobe Photoshop,	
Others Software	Garmin (Etrex), DGPS, Office application packages	

#### SUMMER TRAINING

Two months' Summer Training work on "The scheme of Prashashan Shahro ke Sangh Abhiyan in Sanchore and Nokha. Preparation of layout, Khasra superimposition, demarcation and survey related works (DGPS/GPS/TS), slope class maps and Cadastral maps vectorization & geo-referencing, Land use land cover mapping." From Metro survey services & construction, Jodhpur, Rajasthan.

#### DISSERTATION

Sixth months' academic project work on "Space-Based Information Support for Decentralized Planning (SIS-DP)- "Land use land cover mapping of Chandigarh on 1:10,000 Scale." from **Regional Remote Sensing Centre, West, NRSC / ISRO, Jodhpur, Rajasthan.** 

### **EXPERIENCE**

Nearly **Five Years' Nine months'** experience in Geo-Information Technology especially in Photogrammetry, GIS, Remote Sensing mapping field. Hands-on experience in different natures of projects of Digital Photogrammetry and GIS.

### **CURRENT STATUS**

Working as a GIS Consultant at **Town Planning Department (TPD), Jaipur,** deputed by **Wipro Limited** Though iPeople Business Solutions Pvt Ltd from 28 May 2018 to Till date.

### PAST EXPERIENCE

- Working as a **Summer Training** at Metro Survey Services & Construction, Jodhpur, from 02-May-2014 To 02-July-2014.
- Working as a **Training** at **RRSC-W/ISRO**, Jodhpur, from January 2015 to June 2015.
- Working as a **GIS Executive** at **State Remote Sensing Application Centre**, Jodhpur, Deputed by GIS Consortium India Private Limited, Noida, from 6<sup>th</sup> July 2015 to 4th July 2016.
- Working as a **Project Assistance** at **BISR**, Jaipur, from 12<sup>th</sup> July 2016 to 2nd September 2016.
- Working as a **GIS Consultant** at the **Department of IT**, Yojna Bhawan, Jaipur, deputed by **Wipro Limited** Though **iPeople Business Solutions Pvt Ltd**, from 6<sup>th</sup> September 2016 to 27<sup>th</sup> May 2018.
- Working as a GIS Consultant at Town Planning Department (TPD), Jaipur, deputed by Wipro Limited Though iPeople Business Solutions Pvt Ltd, from 28<sup>th</sup> May 2018 to Till date.

### **EXPERIENCE DETAILS**

Name of the organizati	_	Metro Survey Services & Construction, Jodhpur, Rajasthan.
Designation	on	Summer Training
Worked V Different l		Project:- The scheme of Prashashan Shahro ke Sangh Abhiyan in Sanchore and Nokha
Activities Performed	I	Preparation of layout, Khasra superimposition, demarcation and survey related works (DGPS/GPS/TS), slope class maps, and Cadastral maps vectorization & geo-referencing, Land use land cover mapping.
Period	From	02-May-2014
	То	02-July-2014 ( <b>2 Months</b> )

Name of the	20	Dagional Damota Sansing Contro. West. NDSC / ISDO. Ladhnur. Daigethan
organizati		Regional Remote Sensing Centre, West, NRSC / ISRO, Jodhpur, Rajasthan.
Designation	n	Project Assistance
Worked V Different		Project:-Space Based Information Support for Decentralized Planning (SIS-DP)-"Land use land cover mapping of Chandigarh on 1:10,000 Scale"
Activities Performed	I	Block Triangulation of High Resolution (Cartosat-1) DEM Editing and Orth rectification, Merge Product Generation (Cartosat-1 PAN +LISS-IV Mx), Georeferencing Image to Image, Rectification of Topo-sheets, Land Use and Land cover (1:10,000 Scale), Image interpretation and analysis, Data quality checks & Update Data. Topology create & error remove, DataBase Compilation, Delivery data preparation for GDB, Map Composition
Period	From	January 2015
	То	June 2015 (6 Months)
Name of the organizati		GIS Consortium India Private Limited, Noida.
Designation	n	GIS Executive
Client		State Remote Sensing Application Centre (SRSAC) Department of Science & Technology, Jodhpur, Rajasthan
Location		Jodhpur
Worked V Different Projects		<ol> <li>1)Project: Cadastral Mapping of Tonk district, Rajasthan (Block wise)</li> <li>2)Project: Forest Mapping of Rajasthan (District wise)</li> <li>3)Project: Fodder Crop Analysis of Rajasthan (District wise)</li> <li>4) Project: FASAL Research &amp; Development (Pulses Crop Analysis of Rajasthan, District wise).</li> </ol>
Activities Performed	l	Rectification of Cadastral Maps and Mosaic Village wise Raster and Vector Data, Spatial Adjustment of Vector Data, Forest Boundary Digitize, Data conversion: Shp to Kml, kml to Shp, Dwg to Shp, Image interpretation and analysis, layer stacking, Image registration, referencing and rectification, Mosaic and Subset, Image Classification (NDVI, Unsupervised and Supervise), Maintenance & Updating of Geodatabase, Base map updating and map creation into GIS.
Date of joi		6 <sup>th</sup> July 2015
Date of lea	ving	4 <sup>th</sup> July 2016 ( <b>1 Year</b> )
Name of the	-	Birla Institute of Scientific Research(BISR), Department of Remote Sensing, Jaipur,
organizati Designatio		Rajasthan Project Assistance
Project		1.Cadastral Mapping of Jaipur District     2. Land use land cover mapping
Activities		Rectification of Cadastral Maps and Mosaic Village wise Raster and Vector Data,
Performed	l	Spatial Adjustment of Vector Data, Cadastral Maps Digitize, Image interpretation, and analysis.
	ning	12 <sup>th</sup> July 2016

Date of leaving	2 <sup>nd</sup> September 2016 (2 Months)

Name of the	Wipro Limited Though iPeople Business Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon
organization	The state of the s
Designation	GIS Consultant
Client	1. Department of Information Technology & Communication (DoIT &C), Jaipur 2. Town Planning Department (TPD), Jaipur
Location	Jaipur
Project	Atal Mission for Rejuvenation and Urban Transformation (AMRUT)     GIS-based Proposed Master Plan     GIS-based Zonal Development Plan
Main Project Features	Providing basic services (e.g. water supply, sewerage, urban transport) to households and build amenities in cities which will improve the quality of life for all, especially the poor and the disadvantaged is a national priority. Ortho-rectification, Cadastral Mapping, GIS-based Mapping of Road Network, Building Footprints, and Land Use/Land Cover
Activities Performed	<ul> <li>Rectification of Cadastral Maps and Mosaic Village wise Raster and Vector Data,</li> <li>Integration with Spatial census data, GIS-based mapping,</li> <li>Image Processing for extraction of a vector layer,</li> <li>Generate ULB Data model, Generation Geo-database according to AMRUT guideline with Doman,</li> <li>Feature Extraction (Base-layer, LULC and Building Footprint) from high-resolution satellite imagery (World View -2) as per standard of AMRUT Guidelines,</li> <li>Integration of Non-spatial data (Utility) with spatial data (WV-2), Spatial Analysis,</li> <li>Data QC, QA &amp; Update Data finalization. Topology create &amp; error remove,</li> <li>DataBase Compilation,</li> <li>Delivery data preparation for GDB,</li> <li>Map composition for District Local Body (DLB) and Town Planning Department (TPD), Rajasthan.</li> <li>Town Planning Data Updation, Map-Composition for Master Plan,</li> <li>Orth-rectification of satellite imagery (With Imagine Photogrammetry Tool, Tie Point, checkpoints, Autosyn, Tiling, Ortho-rectification with DEM, Color Balancing, Edge Matching, Mosaic, export into ECW format data, Image enhancement),</li> <li>Prepare Land Base data, preprocessing of satellite imagery, design DEM and DTM, Watershed Analysis, Change Detection and analysis and City Planning,</li> <li>Preparation of Concept Note Project Implementation Support till block level</li> <li>Map composition for Town Planning Department (TPD), Rajasthan</li> <li>Town Planning Data Updation as per Ground Verification (Existing Land Use Land Cover, Town Area, Proposed Land Use, Urban Area) and Finalize the MXD</li> <li>Compose all four maps Data statistics and Map Composition.</li> <li>GIS based Proposed Master Plan Preparation</li> </ul>
Date of joining	6 <sup>th</sup> September, 2016
Date of leaving	Till Working
Daw of leaving	THE TOTALLE

### **NATURE OF DUTIES**

- Responsible for Image interpretation and Analysis
- Desk-Based Data Capture (Digitizing) To Convert Paper Maps to GIS Datasets
- Collection of geographical information
- Maintenance & Updating of Geodatabase
- Data analysis and quality checking of the information coming from the field
- Create a base map and Incorporated Symbols and Annotations
- Providing technical support and expertise to internal staff, and assisting with communication and training sessions related to GIS.
- Finalize the MXD and Map Compose for Master plan & Zonal Development Plan.

### PERSONAL DETAIL

Name	Sk Insan Ahamed
Father name	Sk Md. Mahasin Ali
Mother name	Jayeda Bibi
Permanent Address	Village: Kurumba, Post office: Purbagopalpur, Police Station: Mongalkote, District: Burdwan, State: West Bengal, Pin Code: 713143
Present Address	54A, Lane Number 4 Hawa Sadak, Geejgarh Vihar Colony, Bais Godam Jaipur, Rajasthan,302006
Date of birth	03 August 1992
Gender	Male
Religion	Islam
Nationality	Indian
Language known	English, Hindi, Bengali
Email	skinsanahamed@gmail.com

### STRENGTHS

Hard Work, Punctual, Confident, Politeness, Positive Thinker, Helpfulness

# REFERENCES

1) Er. Suparn Pathak Scientist/ Engineer, 'SF' RRSC/NRSC/ISRO, Jodhpur

Email: s\_pathak@hotmail.com Mb.No. - +91 9414827963

2) Dr. Apurba Kumar Bera

Scientist / Engineer 'SG'

RRSC-W, NRSC / ISRO, Jodhpur

Email: *abera70@gmail.com* Mb.No. - +91 9414915872

# DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge.

sk han Ahamed

Date: **03/11/2020** 

Place: Jaipur Signature: